

Daniel Nieto González

- - Remote work / Cali, Colombia
 - https://nietodaniel.github.io
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/nietodaniel-apps/

Data scientist (384 hours of certified academic training, >4 years of experience), software developer (>2 years of experience) and entrepreneur in services & technologies for biomedical researchers (www.digitalmedtools.com), 29 years. Focused in developing software and analytics solutions to create opportunities and solve situations. My multidisciplinary experience, search of personal and professional growth, and flexibility, calmness and creativity under pressure allow me to solve any situation without problems.

Skills

- SQL, R & Python Developer: Proefficient in developing & testing, either for data science or software development
- Machine Learning: Supervised, unsupervised. Classification, regression, clusterization. Neural networks, trees, boosted alghoritms.
- **Data visualization**: Tableau, PowerBI, R, Python
- Data analyst: Proefficient in basic & inferential statistics, use of statistical software (minitab, stata, R, Excel, etc.),
- Statistical & research advisor: Consultant in biostatistics, statistics for scientific research, scientific data interpretation, scientific redaction, etc.
- Front-End developer: Proefficient in React, Javascript, Bootstrap, CSS, Python, Laravel
- Back-End developer: R, R packages, Python, Visual basic (*Advanced*), C#, .NET, Django (*Intermediate*)
- Language: Spanish: native. English: listening, reading, writing (*Advanced*). Speaking (*Basic*)

Education

Master of systems engineering (*Post-Graduate, currently studying*): *Grade: 4,33*. Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, Bogotá. Formation in Data Science and Machine learning: 384 Hours

- Business Intelligence (192 Hours/4 Credits). Grade: 4,4.
- Methods and Applications in Analytics II (192 Hours/4 Credits). Grade: 4,5.

Biologist (Pre-Graduate): Grade: 4,05. Universidad del Valle, Cali

Work experience

Software developer (10 months)

Contractor in BIREME/OPS/PAHO https://www.paho.org/bireme/, FEB 2019 – NOV 2019.

Planning, design & development of a software aimed to ease the search of academic papers using the PICO (Patient, Intervention, Comparison, Outcome) methodology. (Supervisor: Renato Murasaki).

Data scientist (1 year)

Data scientist in Alianza Caoba http://alianzacaoba.co/, AUG 2020 – OCT 2020.

Prediction of childs under state of malnutrition using different algorithms of machine learning. Project "Analítica de datos para estimar el riesgo de desnutrición de niños y niñas en Colombia bajo Covid-2019", Manos en la Data, CAF (Supervisor: Julio Carreño).

Data analyst in SIT CONSULTING https://sitconsulting.com.co/, JAN 2018 – SEP 2018.

Data analyst and statistical advisor for projects of biological and biomedical researchers (Supervisor: Lina María Villegas).

Work experience – Independent

Data analyst (>4 years). References: Julio Ernesto Carreño, Lina María Villegas, Luis Gabriel Parra

Statistical consultant & data analyst (Independent). JAN 2016 – PRESENT.

R Package developer (Independent). OCT 2020 – PRESENT.

Software developer (>2 years). References: Lina María Villegas, Luis Gabriel Parra, Lyda Osorio

CEO in Project Digital MedTools - (www.digitalmedtools.com). JUN 2018 - PRESENT.

Entrepreneur in documentation and process optimization services for biomedical researchers. Digital MedTools seeks to provide tools and services that ease any scientific research project in the biomedical area. We are focused on supporting the construction of solid, high-quality and reproducible systematic reviews, using the PRISMA and PICO methodologies.

Software developer (*Independent*). JUN 2018 – PRESENT.

Public repositories

Portfolio (React): My work portfolio. Built in react. Available: https://github.com/nietodaniel/nietodaniel.github.io.

LargeDataExplorer (**R**): Powerful package to clean and re-format very large datasets after classifying its variables by their usefulness for machine learning. Available: https://github.com/nietodaniel/largedataexplorer.

(PHP-Laravel): PICO **PICOSearcher** (Patient, Intervention, Comparison, Outcome) searcher built for BIREME/OPS/PAHO, latin american of World branch the Health Organization (WHO). Available: https://github.com/bireme/PICO-BackEnd.

Análisis Exploratorio de Productos en Mercados (Python): Analysis of the sells in Colombian supermarkets using Python seeking to identify the 20 best product sectors for entrepreneurship. Available: https://www.kaggle.com/nietodaniel/an-lisis-exploratorio-de-productos-en-mercados.

Research experience

Grupo de Epidemiología y salud poblacional (GESP), 2018.

Project Neurovirus Emergentes de las Américas (NEAS), 2018.

Design and construction of two digital solutions built in Excel and Visual Basic, for biomedic research: RevEasy: Medical Systematic Searches Optimizer and Screening Tool

Awards

Incentive for academic excellence. Biology undergraduate program. Universidad del Valle. Semesters 1, 3 and 9.

Best ICFES. Colegio Lacordaire, Cali. Grade 11 (2009).

References (Contact info only available for Human Resources of interested companies)

Julio Ernesto Carreño Vargas

Appointed professor. Department of Systems Engineering. Pontificia Universidad Javeriana.

Luis Gabriel Parra Lara

Medical Degree, Universidad del Valle. Junior scientific researcher, Colciencias.

Lina María Villegas

MSc Biomedic Sciences. CEO. SIT Consulting Colombia. https://sitconsulting.com.co/

Lyda Elena Osorio

PhD Epidemiology. Appointed professor. Leader of *Grupo de Epidemiología y Salud Poblacional* (GESP). Universidad del Valle.